David Davis

UI Developer at Apple

Summary

Hello, my name is David J. Davis, I'm an end-to-end developer and I currently work for Apple, Inc. Previously I worked with several of the top digital agencies in the Silicon Valley for clients medium to large such as Chevron, Cisco, IBM, Charles Schwab, PG&E and Fisher Investments.

I'm a U-shaped web developer: someone with a deep breadth of knowledge in a variety of languages. I'm versed in building code that is well documented and efficient; a passion for elegance and simplicity with a background in design.

Experience

UI Developer at Apple

March 2017 - Present

Web Developer at dystrick design

February 2015 - March 2017 (2 years 1 month)

#Web development for large companies such as Cisco, Fisher Investments, as well as numerous medium to small startup companies.

Web Developer at R2integrated

January 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 1 month)

#Web development for a number of Fortune 500 companies, to include IBM, PG&E and Chevron.

Freelance Contract Web Developer at david-james-davis.com

September 2012 - February 2015 (2 years 5 months)

#Hand-code in HTML5, SCSS, JavaScript/JQuery, and PHP.

#Wordpress multisite, custom post type, module and page templating using Mustache, Handlebars.js and JSON.

#Developed PHP w/JSON to retrieve user custom fields at runtime.

#Unit testing experience with Casper.js.

#Accustomed to working on a team in an Agile SCRUM working environment.

#Skilled with jQuery, CSS3, and SVG animation.

RECENT CLIENTS:

DYSTRICK, San Jose CA - A Web Agency

#100% new website development for small to large Fortune 500 companies.

R2integrated, Campbell CA - A Marketing Agency

#100% new website development for small to large Fortune 500 companies. HTML5, SCSS, and JavaScript. Connection to Pardot, Marketo.

BAUNFIRE, San Jose CA - A Web Agency

#100% New website development. Built a custom responsive framework. Handcoded JavaScript animation and custom SCSS templates and a front-end code template for rapid development.

STERLING COMMUNICATIONS, Los Gatos CA - A PR Agency

#Built a new Wordpress website for a large retail company.

HyperRelevance, San Jose CA - A Marketing Agency

#Developed responsive code for a new Charles Schwab Inc. website.

#HTML5, SCSS, jQuery handcode.

#Developed multiple organic jQuery content sliders.

Education

Syracuse University

Information Technology Project Management, 2011 - 2012

California State University-East Bay

Bachelor of Art, Graphic Design, 2008 - 2010

Honors and Awards

Eagle ScoutAll things web, portrait drawing, cooking, philosophy, reading, praying, public speaking.

David Davis

UI Developer at Apple



Contact David on LinkedIn